dokuwiki.org 2018-09-03

# privacy [DokuWiki]

This page explains how and when your personal data is collected, processed and used when accessing dokuwiki.org or any of its subdomains. Basis of all processing are the terms of the [General Data Protection Regulation](https://ec.europa.eu/commission/priorities/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/2018-reform-eu-data-protection-rules_en "https://ec.europa.eu/commission/priorities/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/2018-reform-eu-data-protection-rules_en") (GDPR). 

In the following text we use 

  * “we” for the people managing the website or in GDPR speak: the controller

  * “you” for the users accessing the website or in GDPR speak: the data subject

We're not doing anything different than any other website on the planet, but it's only fair we explain it to you. 

This text was written to be short and easy to understand by someone who is not a lawyer. If you feel something is not as clear as it should be, please help to improve it (it's a wiki after all). 

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files stored by us inside your browser. This allows us to give your browser a short- and long-term memory. 

In general, all cookies we set are necessary to provide functionality on our sites. Details on which cookies are set by DokuWiki are available at Cookies. 

Some of the third party services we use (see below) may also set their own cookies. We explain those further down. Your browser has settings to control which cookies it accepts and for how long it stores them. [How to enable cookies.](https://www.whatismybrowser.com/guides/how-to-enable-cookies/ "https://www.whatismybrowser.com/guides/how-to-enable-cookies/")

## Server Logs

The web server hosting our site will log each page access. This log will also contain some personal data: 

  * your IP address

  * the referrer (where you came from)

  * your browser identification

This information is necessary for legal reasons and to analyse and prevent abuse. This allows us to keep users away who try to crash our server or to have necessary evidence in case of illegal or criminal activity. 

Our server logs are automatically deleted after 14 days. We will only keep log files longer when they are needed as evidence during an investigation. 

## Change Logs

When you edit a page in the wiki, we log the following personal data 

  * username

  * IP address

This allows us to easily block users who vandalize the wiki. And your username allows us to credit you according to the [CC Attribution Share Alike](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/ "http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/") license we use on this wiki. 

## User Profiles

When you opt to register for an account in our [forum](https://forum.dokuwiki.org/ "https://forum.dokuwiki.org") you need to provide the following minimal data: 

  * username

  * email address

  * password

All other data is optional. 

The forum and the wiki share your user account data (both are running on the same server). That means the same information is used in the wiki. You can see and update that personal information in your forum profile. 

When you want to delete your account, write an email to [andi [at] splitbrain [dot] org](mailto:andi%20%5Bat%5D%20splitbrain%20%5Bdot%5D%20org "andi \[at\] splitbrain \[dot\] org") or post accordingly in the [Help subforum](https://forum.dokuwiki.org/forum/11 "https://forum.dokuwiki.org/forum/11"). Unfortunately the forum currently does not support self-deletion. 

## Third Party Processing

### Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a popular free tool to track how users use a web page. It tracks, for example, where users came from, which pages they looked at and how long they stayed on the site. 

This information is useful to us to understand our users better and improve the service. 

We use Google Analytics with the 'anonymizeIP' option. That means Google will truncate your IP address before processing it. This way, no personal identifiable information is sent to Google Analytics. 

Google's servers do see your full IP address, though, because the analytics script is downloaded directly from them. They promise not to use that though – we trust them. 

Google Analytics also uses a cookie to track if you visit a website more often. 

You can easily opt out of being tracked at all using their [Browser Plugin](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en "https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en"). 

### Google AdSense

Yes, we show ads on some of our subdomains (in the forum, for example). Those are provided by Google AdSense. 

Again, we do not send any personal identifiable information to Google, but we do load their script and they do set a cookie to “improve the ad experience”. 

You can opt out of some of their tracking using their [Ad Settings Tool](https://adssettings.google.com/ "https://adssettings.google.com/") or you can just install an ad blocker. We're not even mad. ¯\\_(ツ)_/¯ 

### YouTube and other Videos

Some of our pages may contain videos. We use the Video Share Plugin for that. We use the “privacy enhanced” `youtube-nocookie.com` domain for YouTube videos. That domain will not track your visit. Your IP address will be visible to YouTube's server though. 

Videos embedded from other sources may track your visit. 

### Facebook, Twitter, Google+ Badges

We invite you to join our social communities. To do so we use their social widgets on some pages. These may track you with a cookie. 

## Your Rights

The GDPR guarantees your right to information about your personal data, as well as your rights to rectification, erasure, and portability (e.g. for transferring data). Furthermore, you have a right to restriction and objection of processing your data. 

Feel free to write an email to [andi [at] splitbrain [dot] org](mailto:andi%20%5Bat%5D%20splitbrain%20%5Bdot%5D%20org "andi \[at\] splitbrain \[dot\] org") or post in the [forum](https://forum.dokuwiki.org/ "https://forum.dokuwiki.org") or mailinglist, so that we can work out how we can help you. 

Of course, you also have a right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory data protection authority.
